# Bishal Kumar Sardar

STUDENT

# Contact

- Gramthan-2, Jhorahat,
- bsalsrd5@gmail.com
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/bishal-sardar-297026216/

# **Technical Skills**

## **Programming Language**

- HTML/CSS
- JAVASCRIPT
- PHP
- LAVAVEL
- JAVA
- PYTHON
- SQL

## **Operating System**

- Windows
- Linux

#### **Application**

- Visual Studio Code
- Sublime Text
- PyCharm
- Cisco Packet Tracer
- Virtual Box
- Adobe XD
- Figma

# **About**

I am honest, reliable and self - motivated individual with good interpersonal skill. I am the student of BSc Computer Science (Hons) from Itahari international college, Itahari. I am well familiar about the coding so I joined the IT college to get more knowledge on advance level and also to being a successful programmer.

# **Education History**

# **BSc (Hons) Computing**

2021-ongoing Itahari International College Sundar Haraicha-4, Morang

#### **SEE & SLC**

2018 & 2018-2020 Shree Pokhariya Secondary School Biratnagar-3, Morang

# **Work Experience**

Konnect Nepal Network May 2019 - August 2019 INTERN

Manage the work in the expansion of the no of customer

**Local Customer** 

Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

## **Website Development**

 Developed a website for thekedar's profile and his works and experience

Nepal Telecom

April 2018 - June 2018

# **INTERN**

· Validation of data and provide the feedback

# **Soft Skills**

- BETTER COMMUNICATOR
- CREATIVE THINKER
- INNOVATIVE
- OPEN MINDED
- QUICK LEARNER

# Reference

#### Mr. Pratik Panta

Tutor of Itahari International College pratik.panta@iic.edu.np

# Academic Project Experience

#### **Product Management System**

Java

- Java Swing and event handlers are used.
- The Searching and Sorting algorithm is used.

### **Inventory Management System**

XML, DTD, XSD, CSS

- DTD and XSD are used to validate the XML
- CSS is also added to provide attractive design

### Library Management System

Python

- It was a command line application.
- The data was stored in text file.
- · Error handling is used for critical conditions

### T-14 Training Academic

Prototype Design, Use Case

- The Project is designed in RUP methodology
- Gannt Chart is used for time management.
- Use Case, Collaboration, Class, Sequence diagram are used for internal software structure

#### **Portfolio Website Development**

HTML, CSS & JavaScript

- A personal website was developed
- All the UI are made using Figma.
- It was a static website.

#### **Game Development**

Bash shell command

- A game was developed in Linux environment.
- This project contains loops and conditions.
- · The game is developed for Music band